# Emily Atkinson

68 Old Dairy Drive, Wake Forest, NC 20492 e.atkinson@gmail.com (382) 493-2011

Skilled speech language pathologist with 13+ years of experience in schools and health care settings. Able to properly diagnose and develop treatment strategy plans for communication impairments in both children and adults. Proficient at working with medical teams, parents, teachers, and clients to ensure a positive outcome to therapy. Achieved 98% positive feedback from parents and teachers at current position.

# Key Skills

- Diagnostics
- Written and oral communication
- Case management
- EMR/EHR
- Teamwork
- Compassionate care
- Evaluations
- Client and caregiver education
- American Sign Language proficiency

# Certifications

- Certificate of Clinical Competence (CCC-SLP) from the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association (ASHA), June 2010
- North Carolina State licensure in speech language pathology, June 2018

# Professional Experience

#### Senior Speech Language Therapist

Wake Forest Central School District, Wake Forest, NC | March 2016 - Present

- Develop and implement IEP plans; attend regular IEP meetings with stakeholders
- Overall responsibility for all speech language work in 14-school district
- Supervise two speech language pathologists and one speech language assistant; schedule and monitor all meetings with clients, parents, teachers, and medical professionals as needed
- Work directly with approximately 20 students a week; diagnosing communication needs and developing practical and manageable treatment plans that feature in-school work along with home practice
- Aid and educate parents and teachers on ramifications of client disorders and best practices for treatment

## Speech Language Pathologist

Raleigh Therapy Associates, Raleigh, NC | October 2008 - March 2016

- Integral part of team-based medical management practice; worked with clients of all ages possessing a variety of therapeutic needs, including post-stroke rehab, hearing impaired, and stuttering
- Met one-on-one with 6-8 patients daily, aiding them with recommended treatment practices
- Interviewed and assessed incoming clients; developed treatment plans based on their needs and abilities
- Programmed and modified assistive communication devices for clients to achieve optimal results

## Education

# Bachelor of Arts in Linguistics

University Of North Carolina At Chapel Hill Chapel Hill, NC | September 1999 – May 2003

- GPA: 3.5/4.0
- Minor in Health and Society
- Internship: Shadowed and assisted speech language pathologist at Chapel Hill Audiology, January – May 2003

## Master of Science in Speech Language Pathology

University Of North Carolina At Chapel Hill Chapel Hill, NC | September 2006 – May 2008

- GPA: 3.7/4.0
- Met all requirements for ASHA Certification
- Clinical Experience: UNC Dental School Craniofacial Center; worked directly with patients of all ages presenting a wide range of communication disorders, under the guidance of certified speech language pathologists
- Passed National Teachers Examination in Speech Language Pathology